Guide to the American Veterans Committee records, 1942-2002 MS2144
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- World Veterans Federation, 1953-2002; MS2144 Series 12
  - 10th General Assembly - Copenhagen [2/3], 1963 (Box 219, Folder 2)
  - 10th General Assembly - Copenhagen [3/3], 1963 (Box 219, Folder 3)
  - 11th General Assembly - Lausanne, 1965 (Box 219, Folder 4)
  - 12th General Assembly - The Hague [1/2], 1967 (Box 219, Folder 5)
  - 12th General Assembly - The Hague [2/2], 1967 (Box 219, Folder 6)
  - 13th General Assembly - Vienna, 1970 (Box 220, Folder 1)
  - 15th General Assembly - Maastricht [1/2], 1976 (Box 220, Folder 2)
  - 15th General Assembly - Maastricht [2/2], 1976 (Box 220, Folder 3)
  - 15th Meeting of the Standing Committee for Asia and the Pacific, 2001 (Box 220, Folder 4)
  - 16th General Assembly - Florence, 1979 (Box 220, Folder 5)
  - 17th General Assembly - Nice [1/2], 1982 (Box 220, Folder 6)
  - 17th General Assembly - Nice [2/2], 1982 (Box 220, Folder 7)
  - 17th Meeting of the SCEA, 1999 (Box 221, Folder 1)
  - 18th General Assembly - Rotterdam [1/3], 1985 (Box 221, Folder 2)
  - 18th General Assembly - Rotterdam [2/3], 1985 (Box 221, Folder 3)
  - 18th General Assembly - Rotterdam [3/3], 1985 (Box 221, Folder 4)
  - 19th General Assembly - Manila, 1988 (Box 221, Folder 5)
  - 20th General Assembly - Helsinki, 1988 (Box 221, Folder 6)
  - 21st General Assembly - Bordeaux, 1994 (Box 222, Folder 1)
  - 21st Meeting of the Council - Paris, 1964 (Box 222, Folder 2)
  - 22nd General Assembly - Seoul [1/2], 1997 (Box 222, Folder 3)
  - 22nd General Assembly - Seoul [2/2], 1997 (Box 222, Folder 4)
  - 23rd General Assembly - Paris, 2000 (Box 222, Folder 5)
  - 23rd General Assembly - Paris [1/3], 2000; Series 12 (Box 259, Folder 20)
  - 23rd General Assembly - Paris [2/3], 2000; Series 12 (Box 259, Folder 21)
  - 23rd General Assembly - Paris [3/3], 2000; Series 12 (Box 259, Folder 22)
  - 24th Meeting of the Council - Toronto, 1966 (Box 223, Folder 1)
  - 25th Meeting of the Council - Kuala Lumpur, 2006 (Box 254, Folder 12)
  - 36th Meeting of the Council - Paris, 1978 (Box 223, Folder 2)
  - 39th Meeting of the Council, 1980 (Box 223, Folder 3)
  - 51st Meeting of the Council - Taipei, 1993 (Box 223, Folder 4)
  - 54th Meeting of the Council - Marrakech, 1995 (Box 223, Folder 5)
  - 54th Meeting of the Council - Marrakech, 1995; Series 12 (Box 259, Folder 23)
  - 57th Meeting of the Council - Paris, 2000; Series 12 (Box 259, Folder 24)
  - Anti-personnel Land Mines, 1995-1996 (Box 223, Folder 6)
  - AVC - WVF, 1957-1977 (Box 223, Folder 7)
  - Conference of War Veterans on Security, Disarmament, and Cooperation in Europe - Belgrade, 1984 (Box 223, Folder 8)
  - Conference on Asia and Far Eastern Affairs, 1962 (Box 223, Folder 9)
  - Conference on European Affairs - Luxemburg, 1962 (Box 223, Folder 10)
  - Cooke, Paul - 20th General Assembly - Helsinki, 1991 (Box 224, Folder 1)
  - Cooke, Paul - Conference on Psycho - Social Consequences of War, 1998 (Box 224, Folder 2)
  - Cooke, Paul - Draft Resolutions, 1985 (Box 224, Folder 3)
  - Cooke, Paul - Meeting on Peace and Security in the Mediterranean, 1989-1990 (Box 224, Folder 4)
  - Cooke, Paul - WVF, 1977-1981 (Box 224, Folder 5)
  - Cooke, Paul - WVF, 1985-1991 (Box 224, Folder 6)
  - Cooke, Paul - WVF, 1992-1996 (Box 224, Folder 7)
  - Cooke, Paul - WVF, 1997-2000 (Box 224, Folder 8)
  - Cooke, Paul - WVF Reports, 1977-1982 (Box 225, Folder 1)
  - Cooke, Paul - WVF Reports, 1994-1998 (Box 225, Folder 2)
  - Cooke, Paul - WVF Reports, 2001 (Box 254, Folder 13)
  - Cooke, Paul - WVF Resolutions and Cooke's History in the WVF, undated (Box 225, Folder 3)
  - Council of Europe, 1956 (Box 225, Folder 4)
  - Disarmament, 1979-1982 (Box 225, Folder 5)
  - Guidelines to Basic Rights for War Veterans and Victims of War, 1995 (Box 225, Folder 6)
  - Institutions for the Protection of Human Rights, 1964 (Box 225, Folder 7)
  - International Conference on the Latin Effects of Imprisonment and Deportation, 1961 (Box 225, Folder 8)
  - International Conference on War Veterans in the Face of the Changes in Eastern and Central Europe, 1992 (Box 225, Folder 9)
  - International Covenant on Economic, Social, and Cultural Rights, 1978 (Box 225, Folder 10)
  - International Socio-Medical Information Center, 1989 (Box 254, Folder 14)
  - Military Order of the Purple Heart, 1994 (Box 225, Folder 11)
  - People-to-People Program, 1957 (Box 225, Folder 12)
  - Report of the Special Committee on Hungary [1/2], 1957 (Box 225, Folder 13)
  - Report of the Special Committee on Hungary [2/2], 1957 (Box 225, Folder 14)
  - Report on the Second Conference on African Veterans Affairs, 1963 (Box 226, Folder 1)
  - Resolution on World Hunger, 1985 (Box 226, Folder 2)
  - Resolutions before the WVF, 1985 (Box 226, Folder 3)
  - Role of Women in War - 17th General Assembly - Nice, 1982 (Box 226, Folder 4)
  - Soviet Peace Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 226, Folder 5)
  - Special Session on Disarmament - 10th General Assembly - Copenhagen, 1963 (Box 226, Folder 6)
  - Standing Committee on African Affairs, 1991 (Box 254, Folder 15)
  - Standing Committee on African Affairs, 1999; Series 12 (Box 259, Folder 25)
  - Standing Committee on European Affairs, 2002 (Box 254, Folder 16)
  - Standing Committee on Women, 1993-2002 (Box 226, Folder 7)
  - Standing Committee on Women, 2000; Series 12 (Box 259, Folder 26)
  - Talk Back: The Newsletter of the Internation Council of Voluntary Agencies, 1999 (Box 226, Folder 8)
  - US Council of the WVF, 1960-1978 (Box 226, Folder 9)
  - US Council of the WVF, 1980-1981 (Box 226, Folder 10)
  - US Council of the WVF, 1984-1985 (Box 226, Folder 11)
  - US Council of the WVF, 1992 (Box 226, Folder 12)
  - US Council of the WVF meeting minutes, 1960-1972 (Box 227, Folder 1)
  - Veterans News Service, 1957-1964 (Box 227, Folder 2)
  - Will, Hubert, 1962 (Box 227, Folder 3)
  - Will, Hubert - 5th General Assembly - Vienna, 1954 (Box 227, Folder 4)
  - Will, Hubert - 7th General Assembly - Berlin, 1957 (Box 227, Folder 5)
  - Will, Hubert - 8th General Assembly - Rome, 1959 (Box 227, Folder 6)
  - Will, Hubert - 9th General Assembly - Paris, 1961 (Box 227, Folder 7)
  - Will, Hubert - 10th General Assembly - Copenhagen [1/4], 1963 (Box 227, Folder 8)
  - Will, Hubert - 10th General Assembly - Copenhagen [2/4], 1963 (Box 228, Folder 1)
  - Will, Hubert - 10th General Assembly - Copenhagen [3/4], 1963 (Box 228, Folder 2)
  - Will, Hubert - 10th General Assembly - Copenhagen [4/4], 1963 (Box 228, Folder 3)
  - Will, Hubert - 11th General Assembly - Lausanne, 1965 (Box 228, Folder 4)
  - Will, Hubert - 19th General Assembly - Manila, 1988 (Box 228, Folder 5)
  - Will, Hubert - 20th General Assembly - Helsinki, 1991 (Box 229, Folder 1)
  - Will, Hubert - 21st General Assembly - Bourdeaux, 1994 (Box 229, Folder 2)
  - Will, Hubert - 48th Council Meeting - Bangkok, 1990 (Box 229, Folder 3)
  - Will, Hubert - 51st Council Meeting - Taipei, 1993 (Box 229, Folder 4)
  - Will, Hubert - 103rd Meeting of the Executive Board - Madrid, 1992 (Box 229, Folder 5)
  - Will, Hubert - 105th Meeting of the Executive Board - Ljubjlana, 1994 (Box 230, Folder 1)
  - Will, Hubert - Bangkok, Thailand, 1990 (Box 230, Folder 2)
  - Will, Hubert - Conference on Asian and Far Eastern Affairs, 1957 (Box 230, Folder 3)
  - Will, Hubert - Correspondence, 1957-1968 (Box 230, Folder 4)
  - Will, Hubert - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 230, Folder 5)
  - Will, Hubert - Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 230, Folder 6)
  - Will, Hubert - Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 231, Folder 1)
  - Will, Hubert - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 231, Folder 2)
  - Will, Hubert - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 231, Folder 3)
  - Will, Hubert - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 231, Folder 4)
  - Will, Hubert - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 231, Folder 5)
  - Will, Hubert - Rehabilitation and Social Affairs Committee, 1963-1967 (Box 231, Folder 6)
  - Will, Hubert - US Council Correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 232, Folder 1)
  - Will, Hubert - World Veterans Fund, 1962-1968 (Box 232, Folder 2)
  - Will, Hubert - WVF, 1958-1960 (Box 232, Folder 3)
  - Will, Hubert - WVF Documents, 1962-1967 (Box 232, Folder 4)
  - Willenz, June - 18th General Assembly - Rotterdam, 1985 (Box 232, Folder 5)
  - Willenz, June - 19th General Assembly - Manila, 1988 (Box 233, Folder 1)
  - Willenz, June - 48th Meeting of the Council - Bangkok, 1990 (Box 233, Folder 2)
  - Willenz, June - 51st Meeting of the Council - Taipei, 1993 (Box 233, Folder 3)
  - Willenz, June - Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 233, Folder 4)
  - Willenz, June - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 233, Folder 5)
  - Willenz, June - Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 233, Folder 6)
  - Willenz, June - Correspondence, 1992-2000 (Box 233, Folder 7)
  - Willenz, June - Correspondence with Estonia, 1992-1993 (Box 233, Folder 8)
  - Willenz, June - Correspondence with General Bjorn Egge, 1992 (Box 233, Folder 9)
  - Willenz, June - Correspondence with International Veterans' Groups, 1990-1996 (Box 233, Folder 10)
  - Willenz, June - European contacts, 1983 (Box 234, Folder 1)
  - Willenz, June - GAO, 1991 (Box 234, Folder 2)
  - Willenz, June - Health Technology Proposal, 1991 (Box 234, Folder 3)
  - Willenz, June - Meeting on Peace and Security in the Mediterranean, 1989 (Box 234, Folder 4)
  - Willenz, June - Mozambique, 1990-1991 (Box 234, Folder 5)
  - Willenz, June - Portugal, 1990 (Box 234, Folder 6)
  - Willenz, June - Report on the Situation of Refugee Women, 1992 (Box 254, Folder 17)
  - Willenz, June - Reports to the U.N. Commission on the Status of Women, 1992-2006 (Box 254, Folder 18)
  - Willenz, June - Reports on Women in War, 1992-2000 (Box 234, Folder 7)
  - Willenz, June - Report on WVF Council Meetings, 1984 (Box 234, Folder 8)
  - Willenz, June - Rehabilitation Prize, 1991 (Box 234, Folder 9)
  - Willenz, June - Russian Cruise, 1996 (Box 234, Folder 10)
  - Willenz, June - WVF - Standing Committee on Women Statement to UN Conference on Human Rights, 1993 (Box 234, Folder 11)
  - Willenz, June - War Veterans and International Humanitarian Law Conference, 1986 (Box 234, Folder 12)
  - Willenz, June - Warsaw Conference, 1992 (Box 234, Folder 13)
  - Willenz, June - Women in and after War, 1986 (Box 234, Folder 14)
  - Willenz, June - World Congress of Women, 1987 (Box 234, Folder 15)
  - Willenz, June - WVF, 1984 (Box 234, Folder 16)
  - Willenz, June - WVF, 1988-1989 (Box 235, Folder 1)
  - Working Group on Women - WVF - Copenhagen, 1983 (Box 235, Folder 2)
  - World Veteran [1/2], 1958-1962 (Box 235, Folder 3)
  - World Veteran [2/2], 1958-1962 (Box 235, Folder 4)
  - World Veteran [1/2], 1963-1969 (Box 235, Folder 5)
  - World Veteran [2/2], 1963-1969 (Box 235, Folder 6)
  - WVF [1/2], 1956 (Box 235, Folder 7)
  - WVF [2/2], 1956 (Box 236, Folder 1)
  - WVF, 1956-1957 (Box 236, Folder 2)
  - WVF, 1958 (Box 236, Folder 3)
  - WVF [1/2], 1979 (Box 236, Folder 4)
  - WVF [2/2], 1979 (Box 236, Folder 5)
  - WVF [1/4], 1980-1981 (Box 236, Folder 6)
  - WVF [2/4], 1980-1981 (Box 237, Folder 1)
  - WVF [3/4], 1980-1981 (Box 237, Folder 2)
  - WVF [4/4], 1980-1981 (Box 237, Folder 3)
  - WVF [1/2], 1982 (Box 237, Folder 4)
  - WVF [2/2], 1982 (Box 237, Folder 5)
  - WVF, 1983-1984 (Box 237, Folder 6)
  - WVF, 1985 (Box 237, Folder 7)
  - WVF, 1986-1987 (Box 238, Folder 1)
  - WVF, 1988-1989 (Box 238, Folder 2)
  - WVF, 1991-1992 (Box 238, Folder 3)
  - WVF, 1995-1998 (Box 238, Folder 4)
  - WVF, 07/23/1998; Series 12 (Box 259, Folder 27)
  - WVF, 2001-2003 (Box 254, Folder 19)
  - WVF Constitution and By-Laws, undated (Box 238, Folder 5)
  - WVF Correspondence, 1964-1985 (Box 238, Folder 6)
  - WVF Dues, 1992-1994 (Box 238, Folder 7)
  - WVF Executive Board Meeting, 1987 (Box 238, Folder 8)
  - WVF Histories and Rules, undated (Box 238, Folder 9)
  - WVF General Assembly Rules, 1963 (Box 239, Folder 1)
  - WVF Liaison, 1985-1986 (Box 239, Folder 2)
  - WVF Liaison [1/2], 1976-1996 (Box 239, Folder 3)
  - WVF Liaison [2/2], 1976-1996 (Box 239, Folder 4)
  - WVF Pamphlets, 1961-1988 (Box 239, Folder 5)
  - WVF and the Press, 1952-1954 (Box 239, Folder 6)
  - WVF resolution on Baha'is, 1985 (Box 239, Folder 7)
  - WVF Special Committee on Women, 1994-1995 (Box 239, Folder 8)
  - WVF Standing Committee on Women, 1991-1996 (Box 239, Folder 9)
- Photographs, 1945-1999; MS2144 Series 13
  This series includes photographs of AVC leaders and events from its founding through the 1990s. Many photographs originally appeared in the AVC Bulletin. Notably, the series features photographs of AVC members alongside presidents of the United States and other major political leaders, as well as photographs of early AVC leaders, AVC National Conventions, and other events. Types of photographs include general photographs, events, portraits, and WVF photographs.
  - Photos [1/8], 1945-1949 (Box 240, Folder 1)
  - Photos [2/8], 1945-1949 (Box 240, Folder 2)
  - Photos [3/8], 1945-1949 (Box 240, Folder 3)
  - Photos [4/8], 1945-1949 (Box 240, Folder 4)
  - Photos [5/8], 1945-1949 (Box 240, Folder 5)
  - Photos [6/8], 1945-1949 (Box 240, Folder 6)
  - Photos [7/8], 1945-1949 (Box 241, Folder 1)
  - Photos [8/8], 1945-1949 (Box 241, Folder 2)
  - Photos [1/9], 1950-1959 (Box 241, Folder 3)
  - Photos [2/9], 1950-1959 (Box 241, Folder 4)
  - Photos [3/9], 1950-1959 (Box 241, Folder 5)
  - Photos [4/9], 1950-1959 (Box 241, Folder 6)
  - Photos [5/9], 1950-1959 (Box 241, Folder 7)
  - Photos [6/9], 1950-1959 (Box 242, Folder 1)
  - Photos [7/9], 1950-1959 (Box 242, Folder 2)
  - Photos [8/9], 1950-1959 (Box 242, Folder 3)
  - Photos [9/9], 1950-1959 (Box 242, Folder 4)
  - Photos [1/5], 1960-1969 (Box 242, Folder 5)
  - Photos [2/5], 1960-1969 (Box 242, Folder 6)
  - Photos [3/5], 1960-1969 (Box 243, Folder 1)
  - Photos [4/5], 1960-1969 (Box 243, Folder 2)
  - Photos [5/5], 1960-1969 (Box 243, Folder 3)
  - Photos [1/3], 1970-1979 (Box 243, Folder 4)
  - Photos [2/3], 1970-1979 (Box 243, Folder 5)
  - Photos [3/3], 1970-1979 (Box 243, Folder 6)
  - Photos [1/3], 1980-1989 (Box 244, Folder 1)
  - Photos [2/3], 1980-1989 (Box 244, Folder 2)
  - Photos [3/3], 1980-1989 (Box 244, Folder 3)
  - Photos, 1990-1999 (Box 244, Folder 4)
  - Atlantic City, 1967; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 1)
    From the accession 2009.075
  - AVC clubhouses, 1949 (Box 244, Folder 5)
  - AVC Georgetown School Joint Legal, 1967; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 19)
    From the 2009.057 accession
  - [AVC staff images], undated; Series 13 (Box 261, Folder 1)
  - [imges], Circa 1967; Series 13 (Box 261, Folder 4)
  - AVCers Pix, Circa 1967, 1978-1980; Series 13 (Box 261, Folder 3)
  - AVC Pictures, 1966-1978; Series 13 (Box 261, Folder 2)
  - AVC receptions Capitol Hill, Circa 1969; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 4)
  - 5th National Convention, n.d. (Box 244, Folder 6)
  - Baltimore Health Chapt., 1973 May 20; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 2)
  - Bolling celebration, 1982 (Box 244, Folder 7)
  - Boston N.B. meeting, 1969 May; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 3)
  - Chicago Leadership Meeting, 02/1956 (Box 244, Folder 8)
  - Congressional reception, 01/1967 (Box 244, Folder 9)
  - Congressional reception, 1973 January 26; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 5)
  - Congressional reception, 1973 January; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 6)
  - D.C. chapter luncheon, 1972 March; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 15)
  - D.C. chapter luncheon photos, undated; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 16)
  - Democratic Platform Meetings, 1968 (Box 244, Folder 10)
  - Draft conference, 1966; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 17)
  - Educational conference, 1972; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 18)
  - Evers ceremony, 1969 (Box 244, Folder 11)
  - Human Rights Seminar, 1968; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 21)
  - Human Rights of the Man in Uniform Conf. Sheraton Park Hotel Washington D.C., 1970 March 19 - March 22; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 22)
  - March on Washington, 08/28/1963 (Box 244, Folder 12)
  - Massachusetts State Convention, 1951 (Box 244, Folder 13)
  - Mauldin reception, 02/26/1954 (Box 244, Folder 14)
  - 7th National Convention, 1953 December 4-6; Series 13 (Box SHARED Box 27, Box Original Individual Box 265, Folder Original Folder 1)
    The convention took place at the President Hotel in Atlantic City, NJ
  - National Convention, 1954 (Box 244, Folder 15)
  - National Convention, 1955 (Box 245, Folder 1)
  - National Convention, 1958 (Box 245, Folder 2)
  - National Convention [1/2], 1961 (Box 245, Folder 3)
  - National Convention [2/2], 1961 (Box 245, Folder 4)
  - National Convention, 1967 (Box 245, Folder 5)
  - Convention, 1969; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 7)
  - Convention, 1969; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 8)
  - National Convention, 1970 (Box 245, Folder 6)
  - Convention photos, 1971; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 9)
  - Convention Granit 2 Kerhonkson, NY, 1972; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 10)
  - Convention photos Atlantic City, N.J., 1973; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 11)
  - AVC Convention annd board meetings, Circa 1960s - Circa 1970s; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 14)
  - Convention, 1975; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 12)
  - Convention photos, 1978; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 13)
  - National Convention, 1980 (Box 245, Folder 7)
  - National Convention, 1981 (Box 245, Folder 8)
  - National Convention, 1982 (Box 245, Folder 9)
  - National Convention, 1984 (Box 245, Folder 10)
  - National Veterans Housing Conference, 1946 (Box 245, Folder 11)
  - New England Regional Banquet, 05/1955 (Box 245, Folder 12)
  - Photo essay, Paul Cooke, 1952-1995 (Box 245, Folder 13)
  - Substandard military housing (Box 245, Folder 14)
  - Tyler birthday dinner, 1981 (Box 245, Folder 15)
  - VAVS Advisory Committee, 1949 (Box 246, Folder 1)
  - Vietnam Veterans Memorial groundbreaking, 1984 (Box 246, Folder 2)
  - Washington, DC chapter reception, 11/1968 (Box 246, Folder 3)
  - White House, 1962 (Box 246, Folder 4)
  - White House, 1967 (Box 246, Folder 5)
  - White House, 1972 (Box 246, Folder 6)
  - White House (Truman), n.d. (Box 246, Folder 7)
  - Wisconsin state veterans outreach, 07/1973 (Box 246, Folder 8)
  - Portraits, A-D, 1945-1965 (Box 246, Folder 9)
  - Portraits, F-G, 1945-1965 (Box 246, Folder 10)
  - Portraits, H-N, 1945-1965 (Box 246, Folder 11)
  - Portraits, O-R, 1945-1965 (Box 246, Folder 12)
  - Portraits, S-Y, 1945-1965 (Box 246, Folder 13)
  - Portraits, unlabeled, 1945-1965 (Box 247, Folder 1)
  - Bolté, Charles, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 2)
  - Clorety, Joseph, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 3)
  - Harrison, Gilbert, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 4)
  - Levine, Mickey, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 5)
  - Marshall, Thurgood, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 6)
  - Nathan, Robert, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 7)
  - National Planning Committee, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 8)
  - Paterson, Chat, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 9)
  - Shore, Chester, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 10)
  - Straight, Michael, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 11)
  - Tyler, Gus, undated; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 20)
  - WVF photos [1/2], 1950-1959 (Box 247, Folder 12)
  - WVF photos [2/2], 1950-1959 (Box 247, Folder 13)
  - WVF [World Veterans Federation], Circa 1963; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 25)
  - WVF photos, 1960-1969 (Box 247, Folder 14)
  - UN Secy-General meets with AVC World Veterans Federation Reps (Murray Gross), 1972; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 24)
  - WVF photos, 1980-1989 (Box 247, Folder 15)
  - WVF photos, 1990-1995 (Box 247, Folder 16)
  - Negatives, 1970-1979 (Box 248, Folder 1)
  - Negatives, 1980-1989 (Box 248, Folder 2)
  - Glass plates (AVC Bulletin), 1950-1959 (Box 248, Folder 3)
    Fragile.
  - [images Radino reception], undated; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 23)
  - Misc. AVC Photos, Conventions and events, undated; Series 13 (Box 260, Folder 26)
- Publications, 1947-1983; MS2144 Series 14
  This series includes a variety of small brochures and pamphlets published by AVC, as well as three published monographs: The New Veteran, by Charles Bolté; Women Veterans: America's Forgotten Heroines, by June Willenz; and Dialogue on the Draft, the 1966 report of an AVC conference of that name.
  - AVC's Veterans Affairs Legislative Program, 1947-1948 (Box 249, Folder 1)
  - National Office Newsletter, 1948-1958 (Box 249, Folder 2)
  - AVC Publications and Pamphlets, 1948-1970 (Box 249, Folder 3)
  - Request for Official Recognition by the State of New York, 1951 (Box 249, Folder 4)
  - AVC Brochure, 1952 (Box 249, Folder 5)
  - Dialogue on the Draft, 1966 (Box 249, Folder 6)
  - AVC Pamphlets, 1973-1977 (Box 249, Folder 7)
  - Women Veterans: America's Forgotten Heroines, 1983 (Box 249, Folder 8)
  - The New Veteran, by Bolté, 1945 (Box 249, Folder 9)
- Audio/visual, 1965-1993; MS2144 Series 15; 3.25 Linear feet
  The materials of this series include magnetic tapes, audiocassettes, envelopes, and documents. They range in date from 1965 to 1993 and represent the audio history of the American Veterans Committee in the latter half of the twentieth century. This series includes documents and envelopes separated from the audio materials for reasons of storage. Recordings of conferences, workshops, a debate concerning the draft, radio interviews, discussions about the military-industrial complex, speeches by distinguished guests, and the testimonies of Veterans are all part of this series.
  Many of the audio recordings concern the United States military draft during the Vietnam War. The Draft and the Group Workshop and the Workshop on the Draft and the Individual explore the role of the conscientious objector along with other issues relating to military conscription. Interviews with veterans and professors, including international figures such as veteran leader Magba Kamara of Sierra Leone, are also held within the series. Civil Rights, Human Rights, issues concerning women veterans, and topics such as gays in the military are all discussed in these audio recordings.
  - Dr. Cook's Washington Broadcast WOOK Radio "Citizen's First" Erased 07/13/1965 [1/3], 05/08/1965 (Box 250, Folder 1)
  - Interview of Judge Hubert Will by Frank Weil (World Veterans Federation) Erased 07-13-1965 [2/3], undated (Box 250, Folder 2)
  - Interview by Paul Cooke of Magba Kamara Veterans Leader from Sierra Leone Erased 07-13-1965 [3/3], 05/22/1965 (Box 250, Folder 3)
  - Citizens First Discussion of Military-Industrial Complex between Eric Cox and Tristam Coffin, 08/13/1966 (Box 250, Folder 4)
  - II Draft and the Group Workshop, 11/10/1966 (Box 250, Folder 5)
    Speakers Richard Boone and Bayard Rustin
  - Volume 2 of Workshop on Draft and Individual, 11/11/1966 (Box 250, Folder 6)
    (Speiser - Chairman)
  - Volume 3 Workshop on Draft and the Individual, 11/11/1966 (Box 250, Folder 7)
  - Workshop Draft and the Group, 11/12/1966 (Box 250, Folder 8)
    First 2 inches transcribed and rewound. Lee's remarks transcribed. Last 1/2 inch contains Everly's summary which is not transcribed.
  - Draft Conference Saturday P.M. Summary Session and Conclusion [1/2], 11/12/1966 (Box 250, Folder 9)
    Transcribed completely
  - Draft Conference Conclusion [2/2], 11/12/1966 (Box 250, Folder 10)
  - Draft and Society [1/4], undated (Box 250, Folder 11)
    Chairman Leon Shull, James Fowler, Thomas DeVries- Peace Corps. Transcribed 11/28/1966
  - Draft and Society [2/4], undated (Box 250, Folder 12)
    Donald Keyes. 1/2 Transcribed 12/1/1966
  - Draft and Society [3/4], undated (Box 250, Folder 13)
  - Draft and Society [4/4], undated (Box 250, Folder 14)
  - The Draft and Human Resources Reel 1 - Complete Statement of Betty M. Vetter attached, undated (Box 250, Folder 15)
    Transcribed, rewound 12/05/1966 Mrs. Vetter not transcribed
  - Human Resources #2 Discussion, undated (Box 250, Folder 16)
    Transcribed and Rewound 12/06/1966
  - Human Resources #3 Discussion - cont'd, undated (Box 250, Folder 17)
    Transcribed and Rewound 12/07/1966